We're ministering in music. The words we
say are from the holy book.
The song we sing
is to praise our Lord.
We prepare ourselves for the Sabbath.
As our master comes to teach the word
as he opens the book,
we start with prayer.
All right, brothers and sisters, we're
going to give the choir another hand,
please.
All right.
Now, brothers and sisters, we're going
to have a reading of the law on the
Lord's Sabbath day. We're going to look
at Exodus 20 1-17. We're gonna have a
reading of the law on the Lord's Sabbath
day. And reading today will be brother
Red.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Brother, when you get it, go ahead.
Exodus 20 1-17. Go ahead. And God spake
all these words, saying, I am the Lord
thy God, which have brought thee out of
the land of Egypt, out of the house of
bondage. Thou shall have no other gods
before me. Thou shall not make unto thee
any grave and image, or any likeness of
anything that is in heaven above, or
that is in the earth beneath, or that is
in the water under the earth. Thou shalt
not bow down thyself to them, nor serve
them. For I, the Lord thy God, am a
jealous God, visiting the iniquity of
the fathers, upon the children, unto the
third and fourth generation of them that
hate me, and showing mercy unto a
thousand of them that love me, and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain, for
the Lord will not hold him guiltless,
that taketh his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Six
days shalt thou labor and do all thy
work, but the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it, thou shalt
not do any work. Thou, nor thy son, nor
thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that's in them
is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hallowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shall not kill.
Thou shall not commit adultery. Thou
shall not steal. Thou shall not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shall not coveret thy neighbor's house.
Thou shall not cover thy neighbor's
wife, nor his man's servant, nor his
maid servant, nor his ox, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors.
>> All right, brother. Thank you for that.
Let's go to Ecclesiastes chapter 12 and
we're going to look at 13-14.
Ecclesiastes chapter 12. 13-4. Brother,
when you get it, go ahead. Let us see
the conclusion of the whole matter. Fear
God and keep his commandments. For this
is the whole duty of man. For God shall
bring every work into judgment with
every secret thing, whether it be good
or whether it be evil.
All right. Now, let's go to Revelations
22 and let's pick up 14-15. Revelation
22 14 through 15. Brother, when you get
it, go ahead.
Blessed are they that do his
commandments, that they may have right
to the tree of life, and may enter in
through the gates into the city. For
without are dogs and sorcerers, and
whoreongers, and murderers, and
idolattors, and whosoever loveth, and
maketh a lie.
>> All right, brother. Thank you for the
reading of the law on the Lord's Sabbath
day.
>> Amen.
>> And I want to say happy Sabbath to you,
brothers and sisters.
>> Happy Sabbath, brother P.
>> It's honor and a blessing to be able to
stand before you on the Lord's Sabbath
day.
And I want to say welcome home here to
the Israel God,
Jackson, Mississippi. And reading today
will be brother Red. Amen.
>> Now brothers and sisters, the title of
the lesson today is breaking bonds and
spiritual stronghold.
Breaking bonds and spiritual
strongholds. We're going to look at
strongholds here. that a a spiritual
stronghold
is a deeply entrenched pattern of
negative thinking or repeated or sinful
sin or belief opposed to God's truth
that holds a person in bondage
rooted in deception.
They are like a forfeited mental force
that can manifest as addiction, pride,
fear, or unforgiveness, etc. We're going
to cover several things here today, but
identifying one requires looking for
reoccurring behaviors,
deeply rooted lies, which a lot of it is
dealing with the commandments of men's
or traditions
or toxic cycles that dictate your
choices. Because through our life,
brothers and sisters, we begin to look
at certain certain bonds and different
spiritual strongholds, brothers and
sisters, that we feel we don't have a
good understanding of how to break it.
But we're going to look at bonds also.
Bonds meaning binding to make secure.
Now, bonds refer physically restraints
such as chains. Fathers. Fathers is like
shackles like you see shackle around
your ankles or imprisonment. These are
the figures physical things that we're
seeing with bonds which means binding.
But we going to look from a spiritual
standpoint, brothers and sisters, a
spiritual enslavement,
captivity to sin, or spiritual darkness
or physical or mental infirmities
because we begin to look at chains and
we always look at, hey, physical
imprisonment. But brothers and sisters,
a lot of us throughout our life, even to
this day, are dealing with imprisonment
in our mind.
And we begin to deal with certain
things, brothers and sisters, that will
allow us to break a bond, which we know
a binding bond in the covenant with God
is something to what? to cure us but
we'll break it or we begin to not to
understand the spiritual strongholds
brothers and sisters that's upon us.
Now let's start this lesson now brothers
and sisters in 2 Corinthians
in 2 Corinthians 10 and we're going to
deal with breaking bonds and spiritual
strongholds.
Let's start this lesson off in 2
Corinthians
and let's look at verse three.
We're going to take our time today,
brother Ray. That's good.
>> We good, bro.
Now
verse three, what it say?
>> For though we walk in the flesh,
>> that's right. We walk in the flesh. Go
ahead.
>> For we do not war after the flesh.
>> That's right. We don't want a war after
that flesh. Brothers and sisters, go
ahead.
>> For the weapons of our warfare are not
carnal.
>> That's right. It's spiritual. The word
blessed. For the weapons of our warfare
are not carnal, but what?
>> Mighty
>> mighty
>> through God to the pulling down of
stronghold.
>> That's right. Mighty through who?
>> God. To pulling down what? Stronghold.
That's could be powers of evil, brothers
and sisters. actions, infirmities,
physical or mentally, or your mind like
will say, "My mind is playing tricks on
me." I think they had a song out like
that one time.
>> Y'all know what I'm talking about, ain't
it?
>> Sometime it feel like that. My mind is
playing tricks on me.
But we're going to look at these
strongholds, brothers and sisters. Look
at verse five. What it's doing?
>> Casting down imagination.
>> The imagination's always what? In our
mind, ain't it?
>> Casting down imagination. Go ahead.
>> And every high thing that exalted itself
against knowledge of God.
>> That's right. Anything that exalted
itself against what? The knowledge of
God. Go ahead.
>> And bringing into captivity every
thought to the obedience of Christ.
>> That's right. That's what we're going to
look at, brothers and sisters, here from
the Titan. Bringing into what?
Captivity. So, we want to bind it, don't
it?
>> That's right.
>> We don't want to break it. Bind it
through what? They capted in every
thought to the obedience of Christ. Look
at verse six. Did you go go there?
>> No.
>> Pick up verse six.
>> And have and having in a readiness to
revenge all disobedience.
>> That's right, brothers and sisters.
Having in a readiness
to revenge all disobedience those
strongholds
when
>> your obedience is fulfilled. is when
your obedience is fulfilled. Brothers
and sisters, how you going to begin to
cast down those imaginations, brothers
and sisters? How you going to be able to
deal with those strongholds that we
have, brothers and sisters, in our
mindset?
Because we can't begin to war out of the
flesh. We got to what? War. Our weapons
got to be spiritual, ain't it?
>> That's right.
>> And it's got to be that word, brothers
and sisters.
Because we have a lot of crazy
imagination sometime, ain't it?
>> But see, I like what verse six I wanted
to add because it say having in a
readiness to revenge all disobedience
when your obedience is fulfilled in your
mind. That's that spiritual word.
Brother and sister, let's go a little
further because we want to know how are
we able to be in readiness to revenge
all disobedience. We need to have some
type of weapon, ain't it?
>> That's right.
>> Let's look at this weapon, brothers and
sisters.
And you don't have to have a license to
carry it.
>> Let's look at this weapon, brothers and
sisters. Psalms 144.
Psalms 144. If you just preparing your
mindset for reading, you can carry this
here. Look at this weapon we dealing
with now, brother and sister. Psalms 144
and one. Because we're trying to prepare
oursel for these strongholds, right?
>> That's right.
>> What it say? Verse one.
>> Blessed be the Lord my strength.
>> Blessed be the Lord my strength. Go
ahead.
>> Which teaches my hands to war.
>> Which teacheth my hands to war. This is
your weapon, brothers and sisters, right
here. your hands and what else?
>> And my fingers to fight.
>> Your fingers to fight. What is he
talking about? A fist fight.
>> No.
>> Flipping these pages. Ain't it?
>> Amen.
>> This is your weapon, brothers and
sisters, to flip these p cuz standing up
here when we be going from uh old test,
new test, I hit them pages.
That's you warning, brothers and
sisters. You preparing yourself. These
are your weapons here,
>> right?
>> Your hands reading the book. Let's go a
little further with this because when
you begin the war with these hands, what
happened? Let's go to second Timothy.
Second Timothy.
Second Timothy 2.
Second Timothy 2. And why our hands is
this weapon and we warn? Let's look at
it, brothers and sisters. Second Timothy
2 and verse 15.
Brother, when you get it, go ahead. What
it say?
>> Study to show thyself approve unto God.
>> Unto men.
>> Unto God.
>> Unto God. That's why you won with these
hands and your fingers, brothers and
sisters. Line up on line. A little here
and a little there. Precept upon
precept. To what? To study to show
thyself approved unto God and not man.
Brothers and sisters. Go ahead.
>> A workman that needeth not to be
ashamed. rightly dividing the words of
truth.
>> This is your weapon. This is what you
doing, brother and sister. You are
rightfully doing what? Dividing the word
of God
in truth, ain't it? With the word of
truth, ain't it?
>> Rightfully dividing the word of truth.
If you doing that, you beginning to
what? Break strongholds and what?
Getting understanding.
That's what we warn for, brothers and
sisters, right here. This book here,
this is our weapon, brothers and
sisters. Because what we want to look at
when people understand it said
rightfully dividing the word or truth.
What is truth? It's the law, ain't it?
>> That's right.
>> Because some people, all people say, I
know the truth. My preacher teaching the
truth, ain't it?
But look, go to Psalms 119 and 142
because we want to look at this word
truth. Brother, sisters, I know I got
script early. Media team, my apologies.
Go to Psalm 119 because it came to me
about their word truth cuz everybody can
put a shirt on and say truth, ain't it?
>> Yeah.
>> But let's see what truth is according to
this book.
Psalm 119
and it's 142.
Psalms 119 and 142. Brother, what does
what it say?
>> Thy righteousness is an everlasting
righteousness.
>> everlasting righteousness. And what
else?
>> And thy law is the truth.
>> And thy law is what?
>> The truth.
>> You just read it, didn't you, brother?
>> I did.
>> Exodus 21-17. The law. That is the
truth, brothers and sisters. That is
what you preparing yourself for to deal
with strongholds, brothers and sisters,
in casting down
imaginations.
Now, let's go a little further. Let's go
to Jeremiah 9. Wanted to put that in
there. Let's go to Jeremiah 9.
Jeremiah 9 and let's look at verse
because we got to understand what we
rightfully divided ain't it?
>> Mhm.
>> Let's look at verse Jeremiah 9 and 23.
What it say brother?
>> Thus said the Lord.
>> Go ahead. Let not the wise man glory in
his wisdom.
>> That's right. Not the glory in his
wisdom. Go ahead.
>> Neither let the mighty man glory in his
might.
>> That's right. In his power. Cuz some
people think they power is more than
God's power.
>> Exactly.
>> Because they consider theyel, hey, I am
a god.
>> Little G.
>> Go ahead.
>> Let not the rich man glory in his
riches.
>> In his riches. People think they going
to be able to buy way into the kingdom
of heaven. Ain't it? Mhm.
Just because they and donated a whole
lot of money,
I'mma get in the kingdom.
But see, but let's look what the Lord
say. We warn with our hands and fingers
going through these pages rightfully
dividing the word of truth. Brothers and
sisters, this what we need to glory in,
brothers and sisters. Verse 24, what it
say?
>> But let him that glorieth glory in this.
Since you want the glory, the Lord said
glory in this, ain't it? What is it,
brother?
>> That he understandeth and knoweth me.
>> That he understandeth and knoweth me. We
need to know the Lord, don't it?
>> Exactly.
>> Don't we need to know how the Lord
operate?
>> We need to understand and knoweth him.
And go ahead.
>> That I am the Lord which exercise loving
kindness.
>> Loving kindness. Go ahead.
>> Judgement,
>> judgment
>> and righteousness.
>> And righteousness. Go ahead.
>> In the earth.
>> In the earth. Go ahead.
>> For in these things I delight, say the
Lord.
>> That's right. This what your God delight
in.
Are you delighting yourself in these
things, brothers and sisters?
Loving kindness. That's hard to find
that today, ain't it?
>> It is,
>> man. People kill you over parking space
now, ain't it?
>> Judgment
and righteousness, brothers and sisters,
here on earth. That's what we need to
delight in.
Let's go a little further here. Go to
Psalms 51.
We can go to Psalms 51.
Psalms 51 and verse 17.
Breaking bonds and spiritual
strongholds.
This one to set the little foundation
here. Psalms 51
and verse 17.
What it say brother?
>> The sacrifice of God or a broken spirit.
>> Of a broken spirit. How many people got
a broken spirit? The sacrifice of God
are a what? Broken spirit. Go ahead.
>> A broken and a contrite heart.
>> And a contrite heart. That means a
mindset ain't contrite means what?
Remorse.
Because you understand sin, you
understand when you went against it and
you what? You remorse for now. I
shouldn't have done that. I knew better.
You got a contrite spirit. But see, when
you deal with the thing, when you are
broken
in those strongholds on you said a
broken and a contrite heart, look what
your God say. Go ahead. Oh what?
>> Oh God.
>> Thou will not despise.
>> He will not despise when you broken.
or with a contrite spirit because that
despise is to make little of. He's not
going to make little of or no thought of
it. He going to be considerate.
Let's go a little further and look at
this brother and sisters. See, a lot of
time in our mind, go to Psalm 34. When
our spirits and these strongholds break
us, we feel there's no hope. Ain't it
right? But we got to look at this,
brothers and sisters, and understand
these strongholds to see he's not going
to make little of it or no thought of.
Let's go to Psalm 34.
Psalms 34 and 18.
See, the ones that's broken in spirit
and got a contrite spirit because we
even know when Saul did, Saul know he's
sin, didn't he? Mhm.
Cuz he said that oh I have sinned.
See a lot of us brother and s we in the
fold of God but we are sin willfully
against the word of God ain't it? And we
know we in sin sin against the word.
Psalms 34
and 18. What it say?
>> The Lord is nigh unto them that are of a
broken heart.
>> That's encouraging. Ain't it?
>> Yeah.
>> The Lord is nigh. He close unto them
that are what? Of a broken heart. Go
ahead.
>> And save such as to be of a contrite
spirit.
>> Express remorse.
Sometimes, brothers and sisters, we have
strongholds get upon us. We express
remorse. But then in some way, we still
don't know how to what? Get out our way.
Ain't it?
>> It's a battle, brothers and sisters.
But let's look at this because the Lord
say he's nigh to them that are
brokenhearted and of a contrite spirit.
Let's go back to Jeremiah
>> verse 19, brother.
>> Oh, verse 19. I'm sorry, boy. I like
that. You on the ball, boy.
>> Double duty.
>> Double
>> verse 19. We sure need this one here,
brother. Re
>> many.
>> Go ahead.
>> Many are the affliction of the
righteous. Man, how many time can you
raise your hand up for that, brothers
and sisters? Once you came up under the
blood of Jesus Christ,
>> many are what? The afflictions of the
righteous. See, most people think once
you get into this word, you ain't going
to have no more afflictions, ain't it?
>> Yeah.
>> But it's telling you many are the
afflictions of the righteous. Go ahead.
>> But the Lord delivered him out of out of
them all.
>> That's right. But the Lord delivered him
out of them all. Brother, do y'all
really believe that?
>> All these strongholds that have come up
on us, brothers and sisters, and
breaking bonds, brothers and sisters, do
we believe God going to deliver us out
of it? A lot of time, our faith fall
down so low, it seem like we can't get
up, can it?
>> Let's go a little further with this
here, brothers and sisters. Because we
dealing on a spiritual level, brothers
and sisters, who want you to fail more
than anybody is who?
>> Satan. Satan, the devil,
he want your face so weak
>> that you can't get up.
Many are the afflictions of the
righteous brothers and sisters cuz you
look out in the world seem like they
ain't got a care in the world and having
fun a
let's go to Jeremiah 17
and look at this here brother and
sister.
Jeremiah 17
and let's look at verse five. Jeremiah
and verse five.
The Lord said, "Glory into him, ain't
it?"
>> That's what he said.
>> What it say? Verse five.
>> Thus said the Lord, "Cursed be the man
that trusteth in man."
>> That's right. Ain't it?
>> Go ahead.
>> And maketh flesh his arm.
>> And whose heart departeth from the Lord.
How many of us have departed from the
Lord brothers and sisters?
See a lot of time we look at that depart
we sometime want to look at it physical
a but how many of us even sitting here
today is departed from the Lord in their
mind. Amen.
>> See, we're always looking at physical,
but brothers and sisters, this thing
ain't spiritually.
How many of us has departed from the
Lord, brothers and sisters?
Verse six,
>> for he shall be like the heat in the
desert.
>> Well, once we depart from the Lord,
brothers and sisters, it's going to be
the mind, ain't it?
>> Mhm.
>> Look at verse six again. Take it from
the top. Go ahead.
>> For he shall be like the heat in the
desert. And we know that heat in the
desert hot, ain't it?
>> Yes, it is.
>> We think this hot. Go out in the desert.
I can just imagine when there's heat
hitting off that sand.
So, we got a witness here.
For he shall be like what? The heat in
the desert. Go ahead.
>> And shall not see when God cometh.
>> And see, Uhuh. Read that again.
>> And shall not see when good come.
>> When good coming. Boy, it's good to see
good Lord ain't in the desert.
I'mma roll with you with that one,
brother Red.
>> For he shall be like the heat in the
desert and shall not see when good
coming. How many of us been in that
position, brother? So s we have so much
clutter
>> in our mind, stronghold. We can't even
see when good is approaching us.
>> Ain't that something?
>> Yeah.
Keep going.
>> But shall inhabit the parts place in the
wilderness.
>> That's right. That wilderness, it's like
we in the wilderness now in it. See, we
looking at a field, but a lot of time
that wilderness right here, ain't it?
All them strongholds in our mind. This
wilderness right here. Because we
inhabit those parks, places what in the
wilderness. Go ahead. In a salt land and
not inhabit,
>> not inhabited, brothers and sisters.
Verse seven. Blessed is the man that
trusteth in the Lord.
>> But blessed is the man that trusteth in
the Lord because he don't want to deal
in that heat in the desert. Ain't
because you put heat on anything and you
don't have water of the Lord, what's
going to happen? You going to dry up,
ain't it? And wither away.
Verse seven,
blessed is the man that trusteth in the
Lord.
>> that trust in the Lord. Why?
>> And whose hope the Lord is. and whose
hope the Lord is. Is the Lord your hope,
brothers and sisters?
>> Yes.
>> You see, when we begin to trust in the
Lord,
and the Lord is our hope. This is what
we looking at here, brothers and
sisters. Verse eight, what it say?
>> For he shall be as a tree planted by the
water.
>> By that water. We know that water
separates the word, ain't it? If you
plant it by that word,
you not going to dehydrate, ain't it?
>> Go ahead.
>> And that spreadth out the roots by the
river.
>> That's right. Roots are more than one,
ain't it?
>> It's spreading out, ain't it?
>> Go ahead.
>> And shall not see when when heat cometh.
>> I want y'all to catch that. We read
earlier say it say being in that heat in
the desert, it shall not see when good
comingth. Here when you planted by the
waters and shall not see when he come.
Sometime we ain't going to see when a
trial or stronghold come up on us. Ain't
it
>> right?
>> But if you planted in the Lord, what
happened? What the next verse say?
>> But her leaf shall be green.
>> You still going to stay green cuz you
being what? Water. Y'all see that,
brother and sisters?
>> And shall not see when that he come, but
her leaf shall be what? Green. That
means they got water on them roots,
ain't it?
>> Right.
>> You ain't in the desert drying out.
Brothers and sisters, see sometime
we deal with these strongholds
and it break our spirit so much it'll
cause us not to thirst for the word of
God. That's right.
>> And who you think over there like we say
in the south
ling they chop. Satan waiting on you
ain't.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> He almost dried it up. She almost dried
up. She losing faith Lord.
Keep going.
>> And shall not be careful in the year of
drought.
>> Why not? Go ahead.
>> Neither shall cease from yielding fruit.
>> You still producing fruit, ain't it?
Let's go a little further, brothers and
sisters, cuz we really want to look at
this closely here about these spiritual
stronghold. Let's go to Psalms 69.
Psalm 69.
And let's look at this here.
Let's look at a Psalm of David here.
Let's go to Psalm 69.
See, can any of us relate to this,
brothers and sisters?
Psalm 69. We're going to start in verse
one.
Brother, go ahead.
>> Save me, oh God.
>> Save me, oh God. Go ahead.
>> For the waters are come, come into my
soul.
>> That's right. from the waters are coming
into my soul. Bless those what them
stronghold infirmities and issues of
life because when they come up on you
brother S look what happened verse two
>> I sink in the deep mire
>> I sink in the deep mire that m is what
heavy mud or you can say those feathers
those shackles that's on your feet
brother so the physical shackles
sometime like we got spiritual shackles
on us brothers and sisters why is that
go ahead
>> where there is no
>> where there is no standing because you
in that mud trying to get up and get up
and get up and get up and what you doing
instead of falling.
>> Mhm.
>> Brothers and sisters, y'all see that
sir.
>> I sink in deep mud and heavy mud where
there is what no standing.
Go ahead.
>> I'm coming to the deep waters.
>> I'm coming to deep waters
>> where the floods overflow.
>> Where they overflow me ain't it, man.
That means your mind is what?
Cluttered.
Think about it. I sing in that demon.
I'm trying to get I'm trying to get up.
I'm trying to get up,
but I'm getting a little thirsty because
I ain't what? Being watered by that word
of God, brother and sister, because some
things going to break you. It'll make
you want to turn your back on God. It'll
make you want to give up because we'll
begin to complain, brothers and sisters.
I'm trying. I'm trying. I'm trying. But
I'm in that mud heavy. Can't get up.
>> Now that was verse two. One to verse
three.
>> I am weary of my crying.
>> That's right. How many of us in crying?
You ain't got to raise your hand.
I am weary of my crying. Go ahead.
>> My throat is dry.
>> Go ahead.
>> My eyes fail while I wait for my God.
Man, you in a strong state of a
spiritual stronghold, brothers and
sisters.
But let's go a little further.
Let's go to Psalm 6. Go back to Psalm 6.
See, the Lord said there's nothing new
under the sun. Ain't it?
>> Right.
Psalm 6 and let's pick up verse one
here. Look at another Psalms here of
David here. Let's look at this here,
brothers and sisters. Psalm 6 1-4.
Brother, when you get it, go ahead. What
it say?
>> Oh Lord.
>> Oh Lord,
>> rebuke me not in thine anger.
>> Man, that's a smart man, ain't it?
>> See, you can have that knowledge,
brothers and sisters, knowing that you
are weak and doing wrong, but you'll
tell your God, rebuke me not in thy
what? Anger. Ain't it? Yes, sir. enough
to ask him that ain't.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> Neither chase me in thy heart
displeasure.
>> That's right. Cuz he can come down and
come on us and do what? Kill us.
>> The things we do against God, brother
and sister, if he don't kill you, that's
a blessing.
>> And a lot of time we don't understand
that doing.
Rebuke me not in thy anger, neither
chasen me in thy heart displeasure.
Because brother S, we know if we react
in a hot state, we're going to do
something that we probably regret, don't
it?
>> Look at verse two. What it say?
>> Having mercy upon me, oh Lord.
>> Having mercy upon me, oh Lord, why?
>> For I am weak.
>> For I am weak. Go ahead.
>> Oh Lord, heal me. For my bones are
vexed.
>> For my bones are vexed.
Have you been in that state,
brotherhood, that your bones been vexed?
troubled, afflicted, frustrated, all
those things ain't it? You can feel it,
can't it? Look at verse three.
>> My soul is also sore vexed.
>> That means heavy vexed. My soul, the
whole soul is what? The whole body,
ain't it? My soul is also sore vexed. Go
ahead.
>> But thou, oh Lord, how long?
>> How long? We in that mud. Ain't how
long, Lord? I can't get up. How long?
Look at verse four. Return, O Lord.
>> Return, O Lord. When you look at return,
that mean the Lord was there or you was
there with the Lord. Now you saying
return, O Lord, ain't it?
>> That's right.
>> Have you departed from your God?
And look what he say. Return, O Lord,
and do what?
>> Deliver my soul.
>> Deliver my soul. Go ahead.
>> Oh, save me for thy mercy sake.
>> For thy mercy sake. Gain it. Man, that's
something, ain't it? Look at verse six.
What it say? I am weary with my groaning
all the night. Make out my bed to swim.
>> That's right. Would you look at that? I
am weary with my groanings, brother.
That groaners means a deep, intense,
emotional cry.
>> Verse I mean, keep going.
>> I water my couch with my tears.
>> How many of us have sat on that couch
and cried? How many of us sat on their
couch scratching our head? Seem like we
can't get out our own way to serve our
God. Ain't it?
See, I am weary with my groins all the
night. Make what? Out my bed to swim
and I water my couch with what? My
tears.
>> My tears. Yes, sir.
>> Man, that's something, man.
>> Pull you down, man.
>> Think about that, brothers and sisters.
Sometimes, man, we can have a stronghold
in us, brother s. You don't know which
way to take a left or a right, ain't it?
But see, as we go through this lesson,
brothers and sisters, the Lord was able
to show me how to put this lesson
together this way to get us low so he
can bring us up with thy word.
Let's go to Psalms 38.
Psalms 38.
See, whatever we go through, we still
going to have a little understanding.
There a little light, ain't it? But look
how this start off. What it say?
>> Oh Lord, rebuke me not in thy wrath.
>> Instead of saying that, ain't it?
>> Cuz he know that wrath can end up being
death.
>> Oh Lord, rebuke me not in thy wrath, but
go ahead.
>> Neither chasing me in thy heart
displeasure.
>> Go ahead.
>> For thine arrows stick fast in me.
>> For thy arrow stick fast in me. Go
ahead. and thy presses me sore.
>> Go ahead.
>> There is no there is no soundness in my
in my flesh because of thine anger.
>> That's right. Go ahead.
>> Neither is there rest in my bones
because of my sin.
>> Think about that. Neither is there any
rest or peace.
Peace in my bones because of what?
>> My sin.
>> My sin. Now we got to go get in the
mirror and do a self-examination. Ain't
it? Right.
Verse
four.
>> For my iniquity are gone over mine head.
>> That's right. For my iniquity, my sin
are gone over what? My head. Go ahead.
>> As in heavy burden. They are too heavy
for me.
>> As a heavy burden, they are too heavy
Brothers and sisters, that's something,
ain't it?
Because we got to begin, brothers and
sisters, to look at these different
spiritual stronghold when that things
come up on you. For my iniquities or my
sins are gone over my head.
Because if you in a pool and your
iniquity is that water is over your
head, you only can hold your breath so
long, can you?
>> Yes, sir.
>> And what's going to happen?
>> Drown,
>> man. You going to die. You're going to
be just like that heat that's in that
desert. Eventually, you going to do
what? Dry up.
Think about that, brothers and sisters.
Now,
it says the heavy, it says as a heavy
burden that are too heavy for me. Look
at verse five. What it say?
>> My wounds stink.
>> They stink, don't it?
>> Go ahead.
>> And are corrupt because of my
foolishness. corrupt because of my
foolishness. Any foolishness you do,
brother, you going against God's
commandment. If you go against God's
commandment, you a fool. You foolish.
>> Think about it. Read five again,
brother.
>> My wounds stink.
>> They stink cuz you can smell and you
know them.
>> My wounds stink. And go ahead.
>> And are corrupt.
>> Are corrupt
>> of because of my foolishness.
>> Because of my foolishness.
>> Skip. I mean, look at verse six. And
then when this happened, verse six, what
it say?
>> I am troubled.
>> I am troubled. That's that mind, ain't
it?
>> Go ahead.
>> I am bowed down greatly.
>> I'm bowed down. Because brothers and
sister, when your spirit is broken and a
stronghold get up on you, brothers and
sisters, ain't your head going to be
down?
>> Yes, sir.
>> People going to walk in, you s down a
man, people know right away what's
wrong.
>> Yeah.
>> Even when you come home, they know if
you had a good day or bad day, ain't it?
Mhm.
When you round your brothers and
sisters, you know something is not right
with them. Man, what's I can talk to my
brothers on the phone. I can tell the
way they answer the phone. They'll tell
you the next thing come out my mouth.
What's wrong?
What's wrong? I can hear. I can feel it.
That's knowing your brothers and
sisters. That's why the Lord tell us not
to forsake the assembly together,
brothers and sisters, because we need to
be able to fellowship with one another.
Ain't it?
>> Some of us might need to pull in the
corner and cry with one another.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Console one another.
Think about it. I am troubled and I am
bowed down greatly.
That means man, you weak ain't a man.
>> Yes, sir.
And who want you at that stage more than
anything is Satan.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> I go mourning all the day long.
>> That's right. I go mourning all the day
long, brother and sisters.
That's something, ain't it?
Look at verse eight.
>> I am feeble and so are broken.
>> Go ahead. I'm feeble. That more knees
ain't it, man. You can be shaking, ain't
it? Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> I have roared by reason of the
disqueness of my heart.
>> That's right. I have roared by the
reason of the disqueness of my heart.
Y'all know what disquess is. Ain't
what's another word? Anxiety.
Think about that.
Verse nine.
>> Lord, all my desire is before thee.
>> Go ahead.
>> And my groaning is not hid from thee.
>> That's right. Your deep emotional cry is
not hidden from the Lord. Brothers and
sisters,
when you dealing with that disqueness of
your mind,
look at verse 10.
>> My heart panth.
>> That mean it's pumping a man.
>> Mhm.
>> Go ahead.
>> My strength fellth me. As for the light
of mine eyes, it also is grown grown
gone from me.
>> Well, you almost on ether, ain't it?
Think about these things, brothers and
sisters, that we reading this in the
book, but at the end of the day, we got
to have what? Hope in the Lord. Ain't
it? See, so some of us, brothers and
sisters, in life going to get down right
to this point. See, a lot of time we go
through these things, brother and
sister, but we shame to tell somebody,
ain't it? We don't want nobody know. A
brother don't want nobody know on the
couch crying,
>> right?
>> Soon your brother ring the doorbell,
boy, you straighten up a
Think about it.
But see, my heart painted me in this
pump.
My strength fell at me as for the light
of my eyes. See, you can look in your
brothers or sister eyes and is what also
is gone from me. You know something
wrong in it. Think about it, brothers
and sisters.
Now, when we go through all this, the
Lord allowed me to set this up this way
so we can have hope in the Lord. When
these when things are so heavy and it's
too heavy for you and you lose your
strength,
that last little bit you got,
this what you need to do. Matthew 11.
It's just like if you go to jail and
they say, "Hey, you get one phone call."
So that means you got to use that phone
call wisely. Yes, sir.
>> You got to call the right person, ain't
it?
>> The right one.
>> You can't call that one that's going to
ask you a thousand question.
>> That ain't the one you need.
>> You want one that say, "I'm on my way."
And we'll talk about it later.
>> It's just like this one, brother. We all
the picture the Lord allowed us to
paint. We all way down. But this is what
we got to do, brother. So with that
breath in you, this what we got to do.
Matthew 11
and 28. What it say brother?
>> Come unto me.
>> Come unto me
>> all ye that are labor labor and are
heavy laden.
>> That's burdened. The Lord tell you come
to him ain't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Go ahead.
>> And I will give you rest.
>> I will give you rest. What? When you
going through all this, what rest you
need more than anything? Your mind.
>> Because brothers and sisters, if you
don't have a peace of mind going through
trials and tribulation, you ain't going
to make a right decision.
>> Look at verse 29. What it say?
>> Take my yoke upon you.
>> Take my yoke upon you and do what?
>> Learn of me.
>> And learn of me. Don't he tell us to tie
up the law upon our neck?
>> Yeah.
learn of him. We read that early to show
oursel approved what? Unto God. And if
we going to glory, we need to glory
what? In him.
>> Yeah.
>> But look at your God for what?
>> I am I am meek and lowly in heart.
>> For I am meek and lowly in heart. See,
we got to have that mindset. Having that
mindset of Christ. Go ahead.
>> And ye shall find rest unto your soul.
>> That's right, man. That's what we
looking for ain't it?
>> Yes, sir. Verse 30,
>> for my yoke is easy and my burdens are
light.
>> He telling you that yours heavy, but he
said he is light, ain't it? And he
telling you to bring yours to him.
>> Think about us. The flesh we got when we
going through something and a brother or
sister come to you, it's like, man, I
really ain't got time to hear that, man.
I'm going through something myself.
Think about that. But your God said,
"For my yoke is easy and my burden is
light." Now, he can handle it, can't he?
>> Yes, sir.
>> See, that's giving Jesus control,
brothers and sisters, to direct our
efforts.
Put ourselves under what? His rule.
I can't baptize by myself. God
help me.
And and as we come to him, he telling us
how to come. Let's go to Hebrews 4.
Hebrews 4.
Hebrews 4 and verse 16. How they come to
him. Pick up verse 15. I want to go into
because we got to show this high priest.
Ain't it?
>> Okay.
>> Verse 15. What it say here a few pages.
Hebrews 4. We're going to start in verse
15.
Because look who you coming to.
He should be able to understand. Ain't
it?
>> Verse 15. What it say, brother?
>> For we have not in high priest which
cannot be touched with the feelings of
our infirmities.
>> That's right. All physical and mental
weakness. He understand. He know that.
Ain't it? Go ahead.
>> But was in all points tempted like as we
are yet without sin.
>> But without sin.
But see that's how we got to come
brother and sister. That phone call that
you going to make.
Verse 16. How you going to do it? Let us
therefore come boldly unto the throne of
grace.
>> That's right. Let us come therefore
what? Boldly. Ain't it? Confident faith,
brother and sister, unto what? The
throne of grace. That grace is what?
Your faith in what? The blood of Jesus
Christ.
>> Amen.
>> Let us therefore come boldly into the
throne of grace
>> that we may obtain mercy.
>> That you may obtain what?
>> Mercy.
>> Mercy. And what else? Find grace to help
in time of need.
>> When you down, brothers and sisters,
this how you go to your God. Come boldly
to the throne of grace, being under the
blood of Jesus Christ, that you may
obtain what? Mercy. You got to have
faith to believe this.
See, sometime we say we got faith in
this, but a lot of time we stray away
from whatever the strongholds or
infirmities or affliction we have and
we'll turn our back on God cuz we don't
believe this.
>> Think about it.
See, it's easy to say you got faith.
It's easy to say, "I believe on God,"
until your back is to the wall.
>> See, things can fall up on you, brothers
and sisters,
that you begin to doubt serving your
God.
Because Satan out there can offer you
immediate relief, ain't it?
>> Don't worry about that God there. I got
you right now.
I ain't going to let you suffer.
But see, people don't understand. We go
through the lesson. Sometime the Lord
allow us to suffer
to bring us to him.
That's how we got to do it, brothers. So
that we may obtain mercy and find grace
to help in the time of need.
And that's for me. That's every day.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Now, let's go a little further here. See
the Lord show he said come unto him all
you that labor in heavy burden or heavy
laden. Therefore he said come boldly to
the throne. Right.
>> Yeah.
>> But look how he put a little something
more. Let's go to Hebrews 10. Hebrews
10. See we going to put all this
together. Brothers and sisters.
You going to make your last phone call
count. Ain't it?
>> Make it count.
>> Yeah, man. You got to call the right
one.
See, I know we look at a little funny
like you have businesses talking about
one call, that's all. This how we want
to do our God, ain't it? That's right.
>> One call, that's all. Ain't it? That's
it.
>> And you don't want to be down, brother.
Make that phone call in the line busy.
>> Or you make that phone call and I'mma
get you on this. Y'all make that phone
call and it's on do not disturb. That's
the That's the 2026 Dana, brother Rick.
See, when you call your God, you want
him to answer ain't it.
>> Yeah.
>> But I don't want to be bothered today.
I'm going to put it on. Do not disturb
right now. Hebrews 10 and 22. What it
say?
>> 22.
>> Yeah. Hebrews 10 and verse 22. What it
say?
>> Let us draw near with a true heart in
full assurance of faith.
>> Full assurance of what?
>> Faith.
>> Ain't that's that grace?
>> Yes, sir. Let us draw near with a true
heart
in full assurance of faith. A lot of us
don't have that, brothers and sisters.
We don't have that full assurance. We
lukewarm with our faith. We lukewarm in
putting all our all our things that
afflicting us in the true and living
God.
Go ahead.
>> Having our hearts sprinkled from an evil
conscience. What's going to have your
heart sprinkled from an evil come? What
can what the only thing can do that?
>> Word of God.
>> That's right. But the blood of Jesus
Christ.
He died for us. Dive for us for what?
The remission of our sins. Right.
>> Having our hearts springing from what? A
evil conscience. And what else?
>> And our bodies washed with pure water.
>> With pure water. That word, brothers and
sisters.
See, we can't do nothing without the
what? The blood. Ain't it
>> right?
>> But see, when we begin, I don't care how
low we get or how big or how strong this
stronghold live is. Verse 23, this is
what we got to do. What it say?
>> Let us hold hold fast the profession of
our faith without wavering.
>> Without wavering, brothers and sisters,
this is our profession.
Let us hold fast the profession of what?
Our what? Faith.
>> Faith.
See the Lord said, "Let us draw near
what they true heart and what full
assurance ain't
of faith and let us hold fast the
profession of our faith without
wavering." Cuz see that wavering is
another word is what? Doubt, ain't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Go ahead.
>> For he is faithful that promise.
>> That's right. He is faithful that
promise. But let's look at this here.
How we got to do this, brothers? Let's
go to First Timothy
2.
1 Timothy 2.
First Timothy 2.
1 Timothy 2. Let's look at verse
one.
This is how we got to do it. The Lord
said, "Draw with a true heart in what?
Full assurance of faith." Ain't it?
>> No wavering. Right.
>> No wavering.
>> No doubt.
>> 1 Timothy 2:1. What does it say?
>> I exhort therefore
>> or desire. Go ahead. Therefore, what
>> that first of all supplication, prayers,
intercession, and giving of thanks be
made for all men.
>> Just for Israel.
>> All men.
>> All men. Brothers and sisters, I desire
or exhort therefore that first of all
supplication.
Supplication, brothers and sisters, is a
heartfelt petition or a plea to God.
Just as you crying out to the Lord and
you sitting on your couch warding it up,
man, we got to do the same thing in that
prayer. We got to be heartfelt.
>> Yes, sir.
>> See, that's that remorseful.
That's that contrite spirit, brothers
and sisters.
Prayers, intercessions, and giving of
thanks be made for what?
>> All men. Verse four, what it say?
>> Who will have all men to be saved?
>> For who will have all men to be saved?
Go ahead.
>> And to come unto the knowledge of the
truth,
>> to come into that knowledge of the
truth, to come into the law. Verse five,
what it say?
>> For there is one God.
>> For there is one God. Go ahead. and one
mediator between God and men.
>> And men. And who is that?
>> The man Christ Jesus.
>> That's who you want making no
intercessions, ain't it?
>> That's right.
>> Someone, brothers and sisters, that we
read in Hebrews that know your what?
Your physical and mental infirmities,
brothers and sisters. Who better to be
an intercession for you?
Think about it.
Skip down to verse eight.
>> What it say? I will therefore that men
pray everywhere.
>> Pray what? Everywhere. Ain't it?
>> Yes sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> Lifting up holy hands without wrath and
doubting.
>> Without wrath and what?
>> Doubting.
So you don't want to have with that
wrath of strong vengeful anger in trying
to communicate with your God. Brothers
and sisters,
lifting up your holy hand without what?
Wrath and doubting. Let's go a little
further and look at something here. And
look at this wrath in doubting, brothers
and sisters. Because I want to look at
praying with wrath only to show you the
effects of anger in doubt.
Let's go to Psalm 66.
Psalm 66.
And let's look at this here, brothers
and sisters.
praying with wrath, the effects of anger
and doubt. Let's look at Psalm 66 and
we're going to pick up verse 8 10.
Go ahead.
>> If I regard iniquity in my heart,
>> go ahead. If I regard that sin in my
heart, what happened?
>> The Lord will not hear me.
See that iniquity in your heart,
brothers and sisters, when you going and
petition, you supposed to have a
heartfelt petition to your God, ain't
it? But you got iniquity in your heart.
That's a unconfessed
sin.
Don't you need to repent
>> before you go to your God?
>> God, help me with this, but we'll deal
with this later. Man, we got to clear
everything, brothers and sisters. You
can't have iniquity or sin in your
heart. How the Lord going to hear you
read that again. Verse 18.
If I regard iniquity in my heart,
>> in my mind, go ahead.
>> The Lord will not hear me.
>> Man, that's point blank, ain't it?
>> That's it.
Now, let's go look at something else.
Proverbs 28.
Praying with that wrath, the effects of
anger and doubting, brothers and
sisters.
Psalms 28.
Oh, Proverbs 28.
I read somebody beat you out there.
>> Yeah,
>> I'm going to catch it.
>> All right.
But one thing we can say, brother, I
ain't sleep yet, is it?
>> No.
Proverbs 28.
And let's look at verse
nine.
See, we can't have doubt. That mean that
doubt mean what? You don't have faith,
ain't it?
>> You don't have faith in what you read or
what you believe in.
How God going to deal with you if you
don't believe in his words,
>> right?
>> Proverbs 28
and verse 9. What it say?
>> He that turneth away his ear from
hearing the law,
>> from hearing the law. Go ahead.
>> Even his prayer shall be an abomination.
>> His prayer is going to be a what?
>> Abomination. abomination.
He that turned away his ear from what?
Hearing the law.
See, we just read this. But brothers and
sisters, you begin to look at he that
turned away his ear from hearing the
law. Then the Lord tell us in the law,
love thy neighbor as thyself.
>> Yes, sir.
>> So if you don't do that, what happened?
Even his prayer should be what? Man, the
Lord is directing what he telling. He
that turn away his ear from hearing the
law. Lord tell us not to deal with
idolatry. Right?
See we reading the thing brother. S but
our actions is the one the Lord is
looking at.
>> See we heard the law read today but are
we just going to be hearers of the law
or are we going to be doers of the law?
How many people know about the Sabbath
day in the fold and outside the fold but
still don't keep the Sabbath day?
He turning what his ear from the law in.
>> That's true,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
>> Now let's go a little further here.
Let's go to John 20.
Sometime God word just sting brother and
sisters.
John 20.
And let's look at this here.
We can't be doub we can't have a lack of
faith, ain't it? Let's go to John 20 and
pick up verse 24. This here is one of
the disciples, ain't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Go ahead. Verse 24 here. A few pages.
John 20 and 24. We can't have a lack of
faith, brothers and sisters. Go ahead.
>> But Thomas, one of the 12 called Ditimus
was not with no was not with them when
Jesus came.
>> I mean I mean this was a disciple. He
was there, wasn't it?
>> Mhm.
>> See, that's why we looking at these
things, brothers and sist
what? Doubt.
Some of us our faith still is not as
strong, brothers and sisters, the way it
should be. Now you got a disciplehip
that was there with the Lord. Didn't he
listen to him?
>> Yeah.
>> Don't we still read God's word, but we
still have doubt.
Think about it. Verse 20 25. What it
say?
>> The other disciple therefore said unto
him,
>> go ahead.
>> We have seen the Lord.
>> We have seen the Lord. But he said unto
them, "Except I shall see in his hands
the print of the nails, and put my
finger into the print of the nails, and
thrust my hand into his side, I will not
believe."
>> I would not believe. But he told you
that he was going to die.
>> Die for the remission of sin. These one
of the 12 that was there. But did he
believe him?
>> Nope.
Are we going to believe what we reading,
brothers and sisters, or are we going to
doubt it? Or are we going to be
faithless with it, brothers and sisters?
See, some of in this same boat Thomas is
right today.
But he said unto them, "Except I see in
his hand the print of the nails,
and put my finger in the print of the
nail, and thrust my hands into his side,
I will not believe."
>> That's faithless, ain't it?
>> Yeah.
>> So much that same way, brothers and
sisters.
>> Look at verse 26. And after 8 days,
again, his disciples were within, and
Tom was with them. Then came Jesus, the
door being shut, and stood in the midst.
>> Stood in the midst. Go ahead.
>> Peace be unto you.
>> Go ahead.
>> Then said he to Thomas, "Reach hither
thy finger, and behold my hands, and
reach hither thy hand, and thrust it
into my side, and be not faith
faithless, but believing."
>> But believing.
And that's something, ain't it, brothers
and sisters?
See, the Lord are renewed. Mhm.
>> See the Lord even know where our faith
at.
I don't know where my brother faith at.
He don't know where my faith at. But all
we do, but we know the Lord know it. And
sometime the Lord test us to see where
our faith at. You say you believe me.
But let's see.
See, you see like I was talking with a
brother when you just look in Matthew
6:33 when the Lord say, "Seek the
kingdom of God what?"
>> First,
>> first and then what? I add everything.
We don't believe that, don't we?
>> No.
>> I got to go make this money.
That's faith in believing that. Look at
verse 28. And Thomas answered and said
unto him, "My Lord, my God."
>> Now, my Lord and my God. Ain't it?
>> See, so much like that until the Lord
deliver us or the Lord show us
something. Then I'm going to say, "My
Lord and my God." God want you to say,
"My Lord, my God." When you can't see.
>> Amen.
>> My Lord, my God. When I'm on that couch
crying,
when I'm in that car, head down.
>> Yes, Lord.
don't know which way to turn. I'm going
to say, "My Lord, my God."
See, that's that faith there. Verse 29.
Jesus said unto him, "Thomas, because
thou hast seen me, thou has believed.
Blessed are they that have not seen and
yet have believed."
>> That's right. That's why I want to keep
working towards I want to believe
without always, brother s without sin.
You got to believe. We believe Jesus
died on the cross for the remission of
sins. Ain't it
>> right?
>> Have any of us seen him die on the
cross?
>> No.
>> But do you believe that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Praise the Lord.
>> Now,
you hear this all the time. Let's go to
second Corinthians 5. Just a little
encouragement.
2 Corinthians 5.
Small but powerful.
Cuz the Lord just got through talking to
Thomas, didn't he?
>> Mhm.
>> But see, this what the Lord want to see,
brothers and sisters, from us. 2
Corinthians 5 and verse 7.
You can go make your t-shirt with this
on there, a cap,
coaster or something, man.
2 Corinthians 5 and verse 7. What it
said, brother? For we walk by faith, not
by sight.
>> That's it, ain't it?
>> Yep.
>> That's how the Lord want us. For we walk
by what?
>> Faith.
>> Faith
>> and not by sight.
>> And not by sight.
Now, let's turn the page a little bit.
Let's go to Matthew 17.
Matthew 17. And just look at this here
now, brother. So, we're gonna turn the
page a little bit here because we got to
deal with these strongholds, ain't
breaking the bonds and spiritual
strongholds, ain't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Let's go to Matthew 17.
Oh, red light. They said Yeah. Yeah. Red
already read the lesson. See, read.
Matthew 17.
Let's look at verse 14.
cuz we got to understand it because we
now we coming out what the lack of faith
ain't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Matthew 17 and verse 14. What it say?
>> And when they were come to the multitude
there came to him a certain man kneeling
down to him and saying
>> and saying kneeling down to him and
saying humble himself.
>> Yeah.
>> Go ahead.
>> Lord have mercy on my son for he is a
lunatic and so a vex
>> and so a vex. We read that earlier,
didn't we?
>> Mhm.
>> For he is a lunatic and sore vex. Go
ahead.
>> For often time he fall into the fire.
>> Go ahead.
>> And often into the water.
>> And I brought him to thy disciples and
they could not cure him.
>> Uhoh. M took me to Thomas, didn't
>> Mhm.
>> I just threw that in. They said
disciple.
>> And I brought him to thy disciples and
they could not what?
>> Cure him.
Verse 17, what it say?
>> Then Jesus answered and said, "Oh
faithless and perverse generation,"
>> that's right. "Turn away from the truth,
that perverse generation, oh faithless
and perverse generation." Go ahead.
>> How long shall I be with you? How long
shall I suffer you? Bring him hither to
me.
>> That's right. Bring him here to me. Go
ahead. Verse 18.
>> And Jesus rebuked the devil.
>> And Jesus rebuked who?
>> The devil.
>> The devil. Go ahead.
>> And he departed out of him.
>> That's right. Departed parted out of his
mind. Now ain't nothing walking in him
now. Go ahead.
>> And the child was cured from that very
hour.
>> And the child was cured from that what?
>> Very hour.
>> Very hour. He took him to the disciples.
They couldn't do it, couldn't?
>> Nope.
>> I wonder why not. See this for some of
us brothers and sisters with that lack
of faith. Verse 19, what it say?
>> Then came the disciples to Jesus apart.
>> They put him to the side. Ain't it?
>> Mhm. I ain't ask him in front of
everybody, listen.
>> No, sir.
>> Then then came disciples to Jesus apart.
Go ahead.
>> And said, "Why could we why could not we
cast him out?"
>> Man, that's a good question, ain't it?
Why could not we cast him out? Look at
verse 20. What it say?
>> And Jesus said unto them, because of
your unbelief.
>> Because of your what?
>> Unbelief.
>> Unbelief. Brothers and sisters, your
faith, your unbelief.
Go ahead.
>> For verily I say unto you, if you have
faith as a grain of mustard seed,
>> a grain of a mustard seed, brother s.
That's process that. That's the faith
you need in your God. The grain of a
mustard seed, the smallest seed out
there. Cuz I would think, man, Lee say a
softball or basketball or something,
man. He said a mustard seed.
That's the smallest seed out there.
That's the faith. That made me think,
man, do we really have faith
>> or do we only have faith when we can
see?
>> Do you really have faith in the Lord?
So, you really have that faith. What
would happen?
>> You shall say unto this mountain,
>> you will say to this mountain,
>> remove hence to yonder place.
>> Go ahead.
>> And it shall remove.
>> And it shall remove. Go ahead.
>> And nothing shall be impossible unto
you.
>> That's right.
But look at verse 21. See, this
something we got to add in dealing with
spiritual strongholds, brothers and
sisters, in our lack of faith. Verse 21.
Cuz they asked why they couldn't remove
or cure that man then because of what?
That evil spirit, right?
>> Mhm.
>> Look at verse 21. What it say?
>> How? How be it? This kind goeth not out,
but by prayer and fasting.
>> Prayer and what?
>> Fasting.
>> You got to have prayer and fasting,
brothers and sisters. Y'all see that?
>> Let's look at that. Brothers and
sisters, he said, "How be it this kind
of go going not out but by what?" Prayer
and fasting. Prayer is your what?
Communication with God. And you pray to
the father, don't it? In Jesus' name.
>> Let's look at fasting, brothers and
sisters. It's abstain from food and
water for 24 hours.
This shows humility and surrender to
God.
Intensifying your prayer and what
aligning our hearts with the will of God
and seeking guidance, wisdom and
instructions.
That's what this do brother and sister.
And let's go a little further with this
to understand of this of fasting,
brothers and sisters, because we know
the Lord instructed us one, didn't he?
But let's look at it a little closer.
Let's go to Isaiah 58.
Isaiah 58.
Only go out by prayer and fasting.
Let's go to Isaiah
58.
And let's look at verse five. Isaiah 58.
And look at verse five.
Here a few pages here. We're going to
read this here. Only go out because with
prayer and fast. Verse five. What it
say?
>> Is it such a fast that I have chosen?
>> That's right.
>> A day for a man to afflict his soul.
>> To afflict his soul. I ain't talking
about the devil atonement, ain't it? I
have chosen, he said, is it such a fast
that I have chosen a day for a man to do
what? To afflict his soul. That what I
like about this. Let's look at it a
little deeper. Go ahead. Is it to bow
down his head as a bull rush and to
spread sackcloth and ashes under him?
>> Go ahead.
>> Will thou call this a fast an acceptable
day to the Lord?
>> Go ahead.
>> Is not this fast that I have chosen? Is
not this the fast that I have chosen to
do what?
>> To loose the bands of wickedness.
>> To loosen the bands of what?
>> Wickedness.
>> Go ahead.
>> To undo the heavy burdens and to let the
oppressed go free and that you break
every yoke
>> that you every yoke that stronghold in
that's what being in the way of the
knowledge of God. Brothers and sisters,
y'all see this?
Now you begin to look at this here,
brothers and sisters. That is not this
the fast that I have what? Chosen to
loosen
the bands of what? Wickedness.
And to undo the heavy burdens and to let
the what? The oppressed go free. A lot
of time our mind is cluttered ain't it?
>> Yeah.
>> It's the press.
It's the freed that to bring peace,
brother Sue, because fasting to allow
you to align yourself with God, to allow
him to be able to talk to you. Cuz
sometimes, brother s, we in this rat
race. We don't have time to just to be
still
>> and hear the voice of the Lord.
>> And this is a merciful God. He This is
day he commanded us, didn't it?
>> Yes.
See a lot of time we can't hear God cuz
our minds are cluttered.
So many strongholds upon us brother that
we can't hear God cuz we in that
so-called they said the rat race ain't
it?
>> Man we have to line oursel up with God
brothers and sisters. Now let's go a
little further here to understand. Let's
go to 1 Corinthians 10.
1 Corinthians 10.
1 Corinthians 10 here.
And let's look at verse 13. 1
Corinthians 10 and verse 13.
1 Corinthians 10 verse 13. Ain't nothing
new under the sun, right?
>> Nothing.
Verse 13. What it say?
>> There has no temptation taken you but
such as is common to man.
>> Common to man. Go ahead.
>> But God is faithful.
>> But God is faithful cuz he said come to
him man. That's what heavy laden ain't
it?
>> Right.
>> Go ahead.
>> Who will not suffer you to be tempted
above that you are able.
>> How many people believe this brother and
sisters?
See a lot of us don't believe
who would not suffer you to be tempted
above that you are able because whatever
you going through you think it's the end
of the world it or you think you the
only one going through it but your God
say whatever you going through will not
suffer you to be tempted above that you
are what you able it
>> man that's hope ain't it
>> go ahead but will with the temptation
also make a way to escape.
>> That's just like being in that desert.
You can't see good. You so caught up
brothers and sisters in the affliction
and not seeking your God to understand
it. A lot of time the things we go
through.
The Lord always say what? He always make
a way to what? To escape.
Sometime we can't see the escape man.
See, sometime God be trying to close a
door, but we go, we'll stick our foot
out there and don't close it yet, Lord.
Or we trying to hold on to something the
Lord trying to break us away from.
He always will make a way to escape,
brother S. But how you gonna be able to
see anything of the hand of God if you
are not at peace in humbling yourself so
you can hear your God?
>> How many time we sacrifice fasting
throughout the year? We know one
commanded but wouldn't it just be a
little bit on the resume to do one on
your own?
Think about that.
Think about that brother and sister.
taking that time
to allow your God to talk to you and you
align yourself with him.
Now
>> finishing 13.
>> Finishing 13. Go ahead.
>> That you may be able to bear it.
>> That he may able to do to do what? To
bear.
>> Man, that's faith there, ain't it?
>> Yes, sir.
>> God always in control. Whatever go I
don't care how bad it get in control
because he will always make a way to
escape that you may be what? able to
badg
a lot of time we don't believe that
brothers and sisters let's go here and
look at something here
in 1 Samuel
1 Samuel
going to look at 1st Samuel 7
and let's look at something here we're
Turn the page a little bit here. 1st
Samuel 7 and let's pick up verse three.
First Samuel 7 and look at verse
three,
brother. When you get it, go ahead.
>> And Samuel spake unto all the house of
Israel, saying, "If you do return unto
the Lord with all your heart,
>> with all your heart, that mean coming to
the Lord with what? Full assurance,
ain't it?"
>> Yes. Go ahead.
>> Then put away the strange god and
asteroth from among you.
>> From among you and do what?
>> And prepare your hearts unto the Lord.
>> That's something we got to do, brothers
and sisters. We got to what? Prepare our
hearts, our minds
for the Lord to do what?
>> Serve him only.
>> Serve him what?
>> Only.
>> Only. Got to get all them little idols
out our head, brothers and sisters,
that's taking us away from the true and
living God to serve him what?
>> Only. only. Go ahead.
>> And he will deliver you out of the hands
of the Philistines.
>> Man, we got to begin to obey, ain't it?
>> Yes, sir.
>> See, we always want deliverance, but we
always willing to sacrifice to serve our
God. See, the ones that we put before
our God, them the ones you turn right
around and ask God to deliver you from,
but all you got to do is serve your God.
Think about it.
Go ahead.
>> Then the children of Israel did put away
Balam and Asteroth and serve the Lord
only.
>> Go ahead.
>> And Samuel said, "Gather all Israel to
Mispah."
>> Go ahead.
>> And I will pray for you unto the Lord.
>> Go ahead. And then what?
>> And they gathered gathered to Misper and
drew water and poured it out before the
Lord.
>> Lord and did what?
>> Fasted on that day.
>> And they fasted on that day. Go ahead.
>> And said And said there, we have sinned
against the Lord. And Samuel judged the
children of Israel in Misbah.
>> Go ahead.
>> And when the Philistine heard that the
children of Israel were gathered
together to Misbah, the Lord of the
Lord's Philistine
went up against Israel. And when the
children of Israel heard it, they were
afraid of the Philistines.
>> It was afraid. But look at verse eight.
What it say?
>> And the children of Israel said to
Samuel, "Cease not to cry unto the Lord
our God for us."
>> Go ahead. that he will save us out of
the hands of the Philistines.
>> Go ahead.
>> And Samuel took a suckling lamb and
offered it for a burnt offering offering
holy unto the Lord.
>> Go ahead.
>> And Samuel cried unto the Lord for
Israel.
>> That's right. Samuel, he was what? He
was intercessing then was one
>> like Moses had had done. And Samuel
cried unto the Lord for Israel. Go
ahead.
>> And the Lord heard him.
>> And the Lord heard him. Verse 10. And as
Samuel was offering up the burnt
offering, the Philistines drew near to
battle against Israel.
>> Go ahead. Against Israel. But But go
ahead.
>> But the Lord thundered with a great
thunder on that day upon the Philistine
and discomforted them. And they were
smitten before.
>> That's right. It embarrassed them,
didn't it? See, that's the God we serve,
brothers and sisters. If we believe and
have faith and put the tools in place
that we need with prayer, supplication,
and fasting, brothers and sisters,
taking time to be without God to get
instructions.
Now, we saw that. Now, let's go to Acts
10.
Let's go to Acts 10.
Then, we got about four more after that.
Acts 10.
And let's look at something here because
we want to bring this in, brothers and
sisters,
because the Lord said it all be saved,
ain't it?
>> Yes.
>> And we just looked at Israel fasting,
wasn't it?
>> Yep.
>> Now, let's go to Acts 10 here and look
at Cornelius.
Look at verse one. Acts 10 and verse
one. What did it say?
>> There was a certain man in Cesaria
called Cornelius.
>> Calius. Go ahead.
>> A centurion of the band called the
Italian band.
>> So he was from the Italian band, wasn't
it?
>> Mhm.
>> Uh skip. Now go ahead. Verse two. What
kind of man? This was Italian man. So we
know he won Israel, right?
>> But then look at verse two. But he What
kind of man was he?
>> A devout man.
>> A devout man. And one that feared God
with all his house.
>> That one that feared God with all his
house. Go ahead.
>> Which gave much arm to the people and
prayed to God always.
>> And he prayed to God what? Always. Man,
this was a stranger, wasn't it?
>> Look at verse three.
>> He saw in a vision evidently about the
ninth hour of the day an angel of God
coming into him and saying unto him,
Cornelius,
>> Cornelius. See, hey, hey, this was a
stranger. This was an Italian van. But
let's continue to look at say that angel
came into him, right?
>> Let's go skip down to verse 30.
>> Let's look at verse 30. What happened?
>> And Cornelius said, "Four days ago, I
was fasting."
>> Four days ago, I was what?
>> Fasting.
>> Fasting
>> until this hour.
>> To this hour. And what happened?
>> And at the ninth hour, I prayed in my
house. And behold, a man stood before me
in bright clothes.
>> That's right. The understood that didn't
y'all see that, brother and sister.
There was a stranger, wasn't it? But
he's a devout man, giving himself to the
Lord. Brothers and sisters, that's what
we have to do.
Verse 31.
>> I mean, skip down to verse 34.
>> Then Peter opened his mouth and said,
"Of a truth, I've received that God is
no respect of person."
>> That's right. He's not a respect of
person, brothers and sisters.
But look at verse 35.
>> But in every nation, he that fearth him.
>> But in how many nations?
>> Every nation.
>> Every nation he that fearth him
>> feared him. And if you feared him, you
doing what? Keeping the commandments.
>> You seeking God. Go ahead.
>> And workketh righteousness is accepted
with him.
>> Is accepted with him, brothers and
sisters. But in every nation, I wanted
to go here to show you this thing ain't
just for Israel, brothers and sisters.
But the judgment begin with who?
>> Israel.
>> Israel. Man, we got to be teachers
of this word, brother and sisters.
Because if they don't get it from
Israel, where they going to get it from?
>> Satan.
>> You sure? Right. Cuz Satan got his
ministers, ain't it?
>> Now, uh, did you finish that?
>> Yes, sir. Now
going into closing, let's go to Psalms
40.
Psalms 40.
Let's go go right here to Psalms 40.
Let's look at another Psalms. We started
with one earlier today, but let's look
at this one. Wanted to show you that
about the Italian band, brothers and
sisters, that man, all we got to do,
man, is seek the Lord. Ain't it?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Got to have a good honest what? Petition
to to our God. Heartfelt.
>> Psalms 40.
And this what we got to do, brothers. A
lot of time we get in trouble right
here. Psalms 40 and verse one.
>> What it say?
>> I waited patiently for the Lord.
>> Man, brother and Sue, whatever we go
through, what we got to do? Wait
patiently for the Lord. We're going to I
want you to put a nail on the wall cuz
we're going to look at two instances on
our way closing this out to understand I
wait patiently for the Lord. And that
patient and waiting, brothers and
sisters, is not two days.
A lot of time we get impatient, don't
we? That's right.
>> Two weeks. Come on, Lord. Wait with me
now. I waited two weeks. You ain't
answer me. So put a nail in the wall
when it say I wait patiently for the
Lord. Go ahead.
>> And he inclined unto me and heard my
cry.
>> And heard my cry. Go ahead.
>> He brought me He brought me up also out
of out of an horrible pit.
>> That's right. The Lord, he brought me up
also out of a horrible pit. We know the
thing David went through, didn't it?
Distress, danger, spiritual despair,
personal sin, what the Israel life, all
these things fall upon us, don't he?
>> How many of us, brother, have been in a
horrible pit and the Lord has delivered
us.
How he taken us out this horrible pit.
Keep going.
>> Out of the marry clay.
>> Out of that miry clay. That's that mud
again.
But see, think about this here.
A truck in mud. I know a lot of us been
stuck in a vehicle in mud and stuff,
ain't it? And the more you spin and get
gas, what happen?
>> Get deeper.
>> Oh, you get stuck down. You can't go
nowhere. Okay. You getting deeper and
deeper and then you get more and more
what? Frustrated. Yeah.
>> But look,
if we wait patiently, look what
happened. Next part. What it say? and
set my feet upon a rock.
>> And he set his feet up on a what? A
rock. We know a rock represent who?
>> Jesus Christ.
>> Christ. And set my feet up on a rock.
And then what?
>> Establish my going.
>> Establish my going. Think about that
same truck, brothers and sisters, or
vehicle is in that mud. You getting it?
Gas. And instead of spinning, spinning,
spinning, spinning, but you go over
there and get a board or something, put
up under there and get a little traction
then. Ain't it?
>> Yes, sir. That's how you got to look at
your God.
>> You in that mud that's spinning and
spinning and spinning. I You got to land
on that rock.
>> And when you land on that rock, then he
say what? I set my feet up on a rock.
You got to set your feet up on the Lord,
brothers and sisters. And then he'll
establish my going. Cuz long as you in
that mud
and it's wet, you ain't going nowhere.
And see one thing with us brothers. So
whatever we go through frustration
brings what? Bad decisions.
Because that's why I said earlier
identifying one requires looking for
reoccurring behaviors deeply rooted in
lie or what toxic cycles that dictate
your choices. And sometime toxic is I
don't have patience.
Now, did we finish that, brother?
>> We finished, too.
>> Verse three. What it say?
>> And he has put a new song in my mouth.
>> Go ahead.
>> Even praise unto our God.
>> Many shall see it. Go ahead.
>> And fear and shall trust in the Lord.
>> So trust the Lord cuz your eyes ain't
dim no more, is it?
>> Right.
>> That man came in the last week, man
hanging down. Now he up.
>> That's how it got to be, brother and
sister. Many shall see it in what? Fear.
>> Mhm. and know whatever you've been
through. People know your stories.
People know the things a lot of us bear.
And when people see you come up out of
it and you laying on that rock, man, you
allow other people to feel because they
understood said, "Man, how how man they
got through that?" I don't see how I
could have bared that on. Some of us
look at certain things and we'll look at
handling it different.
>> Yeah. But see, some thing we go through,
brothers and sisters, how low we go. But
see, when God bring us up, we're
exalting who? God. And you can just be a
light to the rest of the people,
brothers and sisters, that if you got
through what you went through, man, I
know it's a God.
>> Because sometimes, brothers and sisters,
people go through stuff. You'll sit
there and look and say, "Man, I don't
want to go through that.
because you don't understand how you
made to get through it.
Everybody's circumstances are different.
>> Verse four,
>> blessed is the man that maketh the Lord
his trust.
>> You got to make the Lord what? His
trust. We can't trust ourselves because
we make bad decisions, don't it?
>> Go ahead.
>> And respect is not the prop.
>> That's right. We not going to respect
the uh the proud. Go ahead.
>> Nor such as turn aside to lie.
>> And we ain't going to do that cuz Satan
always there.
We ain't going to turn the lies cuz we
know he the father of it.
Now I told you hold your place. I mean
put a nail. I wait patiently for the
Lord. Right. Let's go to Luke 8.
Luke 8. We got three more and that'll be
it. Luke 8. Remember that nail in the
wall. I wait patiently for the Lord.
Luke 8.
Luke 8. Brothers and sisters.
See, a lot of time we go do stuff, we
think this going to be a couple of days,
ain't Yeah.
>> Man, you go about a month. Boy, you Man,
Lord, I know the Lord forgot about me.
Ain't
But let's look at this brother and
sisters. This is for encouragement to
understand waiting on the Lord.
>> Luke 8 and 43. What it say?
>> A woman having issue of blood 12 years.
>> How long?
>> 12 years.
>> Man, that's more than a month, ain't it?
>> It is.
>> A woman having an issue of blood how
long?
>> 12 years.
>> 12 years. Can you wait on your God 12
years to be delivered?
12 years. Go ahead.
>> Which has spent all her living upon
physicians.
>> Physicians.
>> Neither could be healed of any.
>> Think about that. Can you put yourself
in that? So much got health elements
now. Ain't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Which has spent all her living upon
what? Physicians. Ne
>> neither could be healed. Any Go ahead,
brother. came behind him, touched the
border of his garments, and immediately
her issues of blood sted. We got to see
who she touched. She got to have faith.
Ain't it? Didn't say nothing. Just
believe, didn't it?
>> Came behind him. We got to look up this
hymn and touch the border of his garment
and immediately her issue of blood what?
>> Stop.
>> That means stopped. But she been dealing
with it for what? 12 years. But look at
verse 45.
>> And Jesus said, "Who touched me?"
>> That's that himmy, ain't it?
>> And Jesus said, "What? Who touched me?"
Go ahead.
>> When all denied, Peter and they that
were with him said, "Master, the
multitude throng thee, and pressed thee,
and saith thou, Who touched me?"
>> Who touched me? Go ahead. Verse 46.
>> And Jesus said, "Somebody has touched
me."
>> Somebody has touched me. I perceive that
my I perceive that virtue is gone out of
me.
>> That's right, man. That's something,
ain't it? Somebody had touched me
for I perceive that virtue is gone out
from me. What is that virtue? Divine
power.
What can heal you, brother and sister?
Is what? The power
of the word. He just she just touched
his garment.
and power came out. Do you believe in
your God that you can be healed from
anything, brothers and sisters?
>> Can you wait 12 years for your
affliction?
Can you wait 12 years for your
infirmities
or or are you going to get impatient and
make a bad decision because you what?
Departed from the Lord. When you depart
from the Lord, that means you departing
from what? His counsel.
And when we depart from his counsel,
brothers and sisters, what happened? Bad
decisions.
Think about that.
Now, did you finish that? Keep going.
Verse 47.
>> And when the woman saw that she was not
hid,
>> that she was not hid. Go ahead.
>> She came trembling and falling down
before him.
>> That's right. He declared unto him and
she declared unto him before all the
people for what cause she had touched
him and how she was healed immediately.
>> She was healed immediately. Brothers and
sisters, for all of us that dealing with
all type of spiritual strongholds,
afflictions, infirmities, whatever it
is, brothers and sisters, if you lean on
the Lord and wait on him, this what can
happen. Verse 48. And he said unto her,
>> he said unto her,
>> Daughter,
>> daughter,
>> be of good comfort.
>> Be of good comfort. That mean be of good
comfort. Bring come into peace now ain't
it?
>> Mhm.
>> Why?
>> Thy faith hath made thee whole. Go in
peace.
>> Thy faith,
brothers and sisters, y'all see that.
See, these are things, brothers and
sisters, going to put us in good comfort
because he told her out of all them 12
years, she went to physicians and
everything, never been ill, ain't it?
touched his garment
>> and the virtue went out of him and he
said, "Thy faith has made thee whole."
Where is your faith, brothers and
sisters? Can your faith make you whole?
But you got to trust and believe in the
true and living God.
There's something there.
See a lot of people don't believe that,
brother Ray,
>> because they'll go out and make bad
decision because they what? They won't
wait patiently. See, some of us don't
want to wait 12 years or longer for
affliction. But we're going to turn the
page on something. Let's look at Luke
13.
Luke 13.
Go right over to Luke 13. So, we got 12
years, a brother Red.
>> Got 12, bro. Let's go to Luke 13 and
pick up verse 10.
See, she deal this lady we just left
with dealing with a blood iss.
>> Let's look here. Luke 13
and look at this here
verse 10. What it say?
And he was teaching in one of the
synagogues on the Sabbath.
>> Mhm. And behold, there was a woman which
had a spirit of infirmity. 18 years.
>> How long?
>> 18 years.
>> That's a long time. M brother and
sisters.
>> Take this to heart. Go ahead.
>> And was bound together and could and
could in no wise lift up herself.
>> That's right. And she had a physical
spiritual. It said which had a spirit of
what? Infirmity of what? 18 years. and
was bowed together, and could in no wise
lift up herself. Verse 12.
>> And when Jesus saw her, he called her to
him and said unto her,"Woman, thou are
loose from thine infirmity."
>> Man, he just spoke it, didn't
>> Verse 13.
>> And he laid his hands on her, and
immediately she was made straight and
glorify God.
>> That's right. Glorifying God. Go ahead.
And the ruler of the synagogue answered
with indignation.
>> Uhoh.
>> Because because that Jesus had healed on
the Sabbath day.
>> Because Jesus had healed on the Sabbath
day. That's why I wanted Lord allowed me
to come in because we want to show
something here about on the Sabbath day.
Go ahead.
>> And said unto the people, there are six
days in which men ought to work.
>> Go ahead.
>> In them therefore come to be healed. Not
on the Sabbath day,
>> but not on the Sabbath. They what they
saying ain't?
>> Yeah.
>> But look at verse 15. What it say?
>> The Lord then answered him and said,
"Thou hypocrite."
>> Thou who?
>> Hypocrite.
>> Go ahead.
>> Do not each one of you on the Sabbath
loose his ox or his ass from the stall.
>> From the stall if he gets stuck. Go
ahead.
>> And lead him away to watering.
>> To watering. Verse 16.
>> And ought not this woman being a
daughter of Abraham,
>> a daughter of Abraham. Go ahead. whom
Satan had bound.
>> That Satan had bound. Go ahead.
>> Lo, these 18 years,
>> 18 years, Go ahead.
>> be loosed from the bond on the Sabbath
day. What better day to be healed on the
Sabbath day?
This is a day of edification, ain't it?
>> Why not, brother? Because you showing
here that it's good to do good on the
Sabbath day.
Verse 17.
>> And when he had said these things, all
his all his adversary will be were
ashamed.
>> All his adversary were what? They was
ashamed when sound like a fool then. And
why not make a whole if the Lord can
make you whole today. Why not today?
>> You already been waiting 18 years. The
Lord can make you whole today.
See, some people can get too holy
or be so overrighteous
they really miss it.
Man, be very careful brother cuz you
don't want the Lord to come and say call
you what? Thou a hypocrite.
Now that was verse 17, right?
>> Finishing this.
>> Go ahead. All and all the people
rejoiced for all the glorious things
that were done by him.
>> That's right. We got to rejoice child
God, ain't it?
But let's look at something here.
Let's go to 2 Corinthians 12.
I want to let's turn the page a little
bit on something here with Paul said. 2
Corinthians 12. Then we got one more
after that.
2 Corinthians 12.
2 Corinthians 12. See, we got to get
understanding on these on spiritual
holes or or infirmities, brother. So,
because we just did one, what was 12
years, right?
>> Mhm.
>> 18 years, right?
>> Right.
>> But let's look here what Paul said here.
We got to get understanding, brother.
So, that why the Lord said war without
hands and finger to get understanding
to know what you dealing with or what
you going through. Now look at 2
Corinthians 12 and look at verse one
here.
Go ahead.
>> It is not expedient for me doubtless to
glory.
>> That's right. Go ahead.
>> I will come to vision and revelation of
the Lord.
>> That's right. Skip down to verse five.
What it say?
>> Of such and one will I glory.
>> Will I glory
>> yet? On myself I will not glory.
>> That's right. I would not glory on
myself but what?
>> But in mine infirmities.
>> But in what?
>> My infirmities.
>> But in my infirmities. put you a marker
there. See, you got to begin to
understand sometime what the Lord is
doing, brothers and sisters. Yet of
myself, I would not glory, but what? In
my what?
>> Infirmities, right?
>> That's physical or spiritual
infirmities, brothers and sisters. But
look at verse six. What it say?
>> For though I would desire to glory,
>> but I desire to glory. Go ahead.
>> I shall not be a fool.
>> Go ahead.
>> For I will say the truth.
>> Go ahead. But now I forbear, lest any
man should think of me above that which
I seeth me to be.
>> That's right. Go ahead.
>> Or what that he heareth of me.
>> Go ahead.
>> Unless I should be exalted above measure
through the abundance of the revelation.
>> Of revelations. Go ahead.
>> There was given to me a thorn in the
flesh.
>> See, that was given to me a thorn what?
>> In the flesh.
>> In the flesh from who?
>> Go ahead.
>> The messenger of Satan to buffet me.
>> To buffet me. Ain't it? Yes,
>> that's the infirmity, ain't it?
>> But look at it. Go ahead.
>> Lest I should be exalted above measure.
>> But go ahead.
>> For this thing I besought the Lord
thrice.
>> See, he said, but for this thing I
besought what? The Lord
>> thrice.
>> Thrice in it.
>> Mhm.
>> I need to know what's going on here. I
was given to me a thorn in the flesh.
What? The measure of Satan to what? To
buffet me.
>> Mhm.
>> Go ahead.
>> That it might depart from me.
>> That it might depart from me. And he
said unto me,
>> he said unto me, you talking about
power. Go ahead. And he said unto me,
what?
>> My grace is sufficient for thee.
>> That's right. My grace is what?
>> Sufficient.
>> Sufficient for thee. Why?
>> For my strength is made perfect in
weakness.
>> Brother Sen, you begin to look at this.
Something the Lord put upon us, brothers
and sisters, is there to save us.
You got to understand this here. For my
strength has made me what? Perfect in my
weakness. Sometimes, brothers and
sisters, the things you go through might
be the things that you need to be able
to deal with so you can continue gloring
your God.
>> See, sometime Lord can lose something on
you and you, man, you going crazy. See,
sometime you look at certain things,
brothers and sisters,
might not be the best example, but I
know a lot of times you hear people
living paycheck to paycheck. Ain't it?
Sometime that paycheck to paycheck might
get you in the kingdom
>> because you know every time you put food
on your table, you know God made a way.
>> You see what I'm saying?
>> Yeah.
>> Something we got to look at that little
infirmity of that little illness,
whatever you dealing with
might you every day to get into the
kingdom of God. See, the Lord won't look
at effort.
He ain't never said we ain't going to
get in there that we might not be
hurting. Who don't hurt when they get up
now you get a certain age. We ain't 20
no more.
Some things brother and sister we got to
look and get guidance.
>> That's right.
>> That's what prayer and fast command to
talk to your God. Some things that you
trying to have removed in some case
might be the exact thing that can help
get you in the kingdom.
>> Think about it. But you got to get
understanding.
>> Yes.
My grace is sufficient for thee, for my
strength is made perfect in what?
Weakness.
>> Most gladly, therefore, will I rather
glory in my infirmities. That the power
of Christ may rest upon me.
>> That the power of Christ may rest upon
you, brother and sister. Because you
knowing, brothers and sisters, in this,
man, is keeping me humble.
>> Yes.
>> It's keeping me thanking him every day.
Think about that, brother and sister.
That just food for thought there. Did we
finish that?
>> We at verse 10.
>> Verse 10. What it say?
>> Therefore, I take pleasure in infirmity.
>> That's right. Cuz it could be saving me.
Go ahead.
>> In reproaches, in necessities, in
persecution, in distress, for Christ's
sake. For when I am weak, then am I
strong.
>> I am strong. Because when I'm weak, who
are you turning and leaning on?
>> Jesus.
>> The Lord. Then I am what? strong,
brother. Sue, because you continue to do
what? Lean on your God.
>> Because you want, as it say, when you
are pulled out that horrible pit, you
want to land up on put your feet up on
what? That rock on Christ, brothers and
sisters.
>> That's right.
>> Now, last place, first Peter 2. This
going to sum this up here. What we just
read here in the whole lesson.
One spot Lord showed it to us, man. Got
to have it. Got to have
read you right,
man. I read that. I said, "Man, got to
put that in. I got to have this."
>> All right.
>> Cuz we know we went one way the whole
way or the less. But at the end, we want
to put that in there. That's why you got
to have discernment. That's why you got
to seek your God to understand that some
things that can be crippling you might
be the same exact thing that get you in
the kingdom.
First Peter 2. Mhm.
>> This the last place.
First Peter 2 and verse 20. Brother,
what it say?
>> For what glory is it if when ye be
buffeted for your fault?
>> For your fault. We can be buffed for
them faults, ain't it?
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead.
>> You shall take it patiently.
>> Take it what?
>> Patiently.
>> Patiently. Go ahead.
>> But if when ye do well, ye suffer for
it. Ye take it patiently. This is
acceptable with God.
>> That's it, ain't it? Whichever way it
go, brothers and sisters, take it what?
>> Patiently.
>> Thank you for your time.
>> Right.
Hey,
hey, hey.